Finding aid for the Derek Whipple Collection of Zines, 1990-2003 LSC.2306
UCLA Library Special Collections
Derek Whipple collection of zines
1990-2003
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2306
5 linear feet (13 boxes)
Maximumrocknroll is a San Francisco based punk rock fanzine established in 1982. The collection includes a nearly complete chronology of issues from 1991-2003, along with a small assortment of punk rock zines from 1992-2003 including Book Your Own Fucking Life, Razorcake, Suburban Voice, Heartattack, and Linfit.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Derek Whipple, 2016.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9980255103606533
Biography/History
A collection of punk zines, largely of Maximumrocknroll, and assorted issues of Book Your Own Fucking Life, Razorcake, Heartattack, Linfit, and Suburban Voice, donated by Derek Whipple. Derek Whipple is a frequent contributor to Razorcake zine. Whipple also works as a camera operator in the television and film industry.
San Francisco's Maximumrocknroll is one of the world's longest running punk zines. Beginning in 1977 as a radio show on KPFA in Berkley, the program eventually moved to print form and officially became a fanzine in 1982. Since then, Maximumrocknroll has become not only a highly regarded punk zine, but also a record label, radio podcast, and news source for a global punk rock community.
Scope and Content
This collection of zines covers a period from 1990 to 2003, mostly containing issues of Maximumrocknroll in chronological order from the years 1990-2003, but contains other zines including Book Your Own Fucking Life, Razorcake, Heartattack, Suburban Voice, and Linfit. The assortment of zines vary from glossy front covers to photocopied paper. All zines are from California except for Suburban Voice, from Massachusetts.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Maximumrocknroll, 1990-2003
Series 2: Book Your Own Fucking Life, 1992-2001
Series 3. Other zines, 2003
Zines; Punk culture -- California -- 20th century
- Series 1: Maximumrocknroll, 1990-2003
  Scope and Content
  Collection includes a near-complete chronological run of Maximumrocknroll from 1990-2003 that belonged to Derek Whipple. Content of zines include interviews, music reviews, scene reports, photos, and artwork with punk bands and artists.
  Arrangement
  Maximumrocknroll zines arranged chronologically by year and issue series number, from 1990-2003.
  - Nos. 91-93, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 94-96, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 97-99, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 100 (pts. 1+2), 101, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 102-104, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nos. 107-109, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nos. 110 (pts. 1+2), 111, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 112-114, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 115-117, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 118-120, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 121-123, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nos. 124-126, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 127-128, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 129-130, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Nos.131-132, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 133-135, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Nos. 136-138, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Nos. 139-141, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 142-144, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 145-147, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 148-150, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 151 (pts. 1+2), 152, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Nos. 153-154, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 155-156 (pts 1+2), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 157-159, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 160-162, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 163-165, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nos. 166-168, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 169-171, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 172 (2 copies), 173, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 174-176, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 177-179, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 180-182, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 183-185, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 186-189, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 190-192, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 193-194, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 195-197 (2 copies), 1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 198-200, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 201-203, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 204-206, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 207-210, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 211-213, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 213-214 (2 copies), 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 215-217, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 218,220-221, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 222-225, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 226-229, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 229-231, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 232-234, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Nos. 235-237, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 238-240, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Nos. 241-243, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Nos. 244-245, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Book Your Own Fucking Life, 1992-2001
  Seven issues of Book Your Own Fucking Life from 1992-2001, that belonged to Derek Whipple. Content of zines include interviews, music reviews, scene reports, photos, and artwork with punk bands and artists.
  Book Your Own Fucking Life zines arranged by year and issue series number.
  - Nos. 1-2, 4-5, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Nos. 6, 8-9, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Other zines, 2003
  Four punk zines from 2003. All zines from California except for Suburban Voice, from Massachusetts. Owned by Derek Whipple. Content of zines include interviews, music reviews, scene reports, photos, and artwork with punk bands and artists.
  Arranged alphabetically
  - Heartattack No. 38, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lintfit No. 1, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Razorcake No. 15, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Suburban Voice No. 46, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 4)